肯∶西维尔医生,
Ken: So, what we have is a stock, which should yield significant profits, Dr.
我们有一支一定会让你挣大钱的股.
Seaver.
杰森∶叫我杰森就好了.
Jason: Please, call me Jason.
肯∶但是,杰森,我不得不告诉你所有的股票都可能跌的.
Ken: But, I also have to tell you that all stocks can go down, Jason.
奶奶∶儿子,肯负责我们所有的投资呢;我们信赖他.
Grandma: Son, Ken handles all of our investments; we swear by him.
威利∶哦!天哪!讨厌,我们完全相信他!
Wally: Oh, gosh, darn it, we do!
杰森∶当西维尔医生就不错了.
Jason: Dr.Seaver'll be fine.
麦琪∶肯,我们不想再听下去了..
Maggie: Ken, I think we've heard enough.
杰森∶是,我们没有兴趣.
Jason: Yeah, we're not interested.
麦琪∶我们要投资.
Maggie: We'll invest.
杰森∶哦!?
Jason: Oh?
麦琪∶失礼一下.
Maggie: Excuse us.Jason,
杰森,
your mother went to the trouble of brining her stock broker all the way
是你妈妈不辞辛劳地把她的股票经纪人带到我们家来的.
out here.
杰森∶麦琪,
Jason: Maggie, he's just a boy.
他不过是个乳臭未干的家伙;我已经把钱给了一个乳臭未干的家伙了,
He doesn't even shave; I already give money to a kid who doesn't shave,
那就是迈克.
his name's Mike.
麦琪∶好啊!你就让你妈妈尴尬吧.
Maggie: Fine!You embarrass your mother.
杰森∶肯,我们...呃,我们愿意投资.
Jason: Ken, look, we...errm...We'd love to invest.
肯:太好了.我们需要一千美元的支票.
Ken: Well that's great.Well, I'll need a cheque for a thousand Dollars.
开萝尔∶大家好!
Carol: Hello everybody!
奶奶∶嗨开萝尔!
Grandma: Hey Carol!
开萝尔∶威利爷爷!
Carol: Grandpa Wally!
奶奶∶你总算回来了!你去哪里了?
Grandma: There you are!Where have you been?
开萝尔∶和朋友去逛街了.我不知道你们要来.
Carol: Shopping with friends.I didn't know you'd be here.
杰森∶哦,开萝尔,你存了不少钱吧.
Jason: Yeah.You saved some big time money, Carol.
奶奶∶开萝尔,过来见见肯,股票经纪人,
Grandma: Can you meet Ken?Stock broker, recent Harvard graduate.Carol Seaver.
刚从哈佛大学毕业.这是开萝尔西维尔.这是肯Single.
Ken Single.
肯∶哦!Singleton.你好开萝尔.久仰大名.
Ken: Oh, Singleton.Hi Carol.I've heard a lot about you.
开萝尔∶你好.
Carol: Hi.
奶奶∶哦!我为我这个美丽,
Grandma: Oh, I'm very proud of my beautiful,
聪明以及完全独立的孙女感到自豪!
intelligent and completely unattached granddaughter.
开萝尔∶好了,我楼上还有一大堆事情要做呢.再见.
Carol: Well, I've got a lot of stuff to do upstairs.Bye.
奶奶∶但是开萝尔..
Grandma: But Carol...
杰森∶行了,肯!给你...1000美元!
Jason: Alright Ken!Here you are...one thousand Dollars!
肯∶谢谢医生西维尔!哦!……你还没有签字.
Ken: Thank you Dr.Seaver.Oh...you forgot to sign it.
杰森∶哦!真是的.好了.
Jason: Oh!Imagine that.Alright.
Ken: Well, Mrs.Seaver, Wally, Urma, I hope to see you soon
奶奶∶哦!希望很快.
Grandma: Oh, hopefully very soon.
杰森∶肯,再见.
Jason: Bye bye Ken.
麦琪∶肯,再见.
Maggie: Bye Ken.
奶奶∶你们觉得怎么样?
Grandma: Well, what do you think?
杰森∶妈妈,我认为这根本就是冒险投资.
Jason: Well, Mom, I think it could be a risky investment...
奶奶∶哦!杰森,
Grandma: Oh, not about the investment, Jason.
我不是问投资.
Now I didn't have him out here to sell you kids.
我把他带来这里不是让你们做投资的.我是带他过来见见开萝尔的.
I brought him out here to meet Carol.
杰森和麦琪∶真的!?
Jason and Maggie: You did!?
奶奶∶难道你们不觉得他很适合她吗?
Grandma: Well, don't you think he's just perfect for her?
麦琪∶事实上,他是……
Maggie: Well actually, he is...
杰森∶打扰一下,
Jason: Well excuse me, but Ken,
我刚才开1000美元支票给他的肯,
the guy I just wrote a cheque for a thousand Dollars to,
到底有没有为你们打理投资?
does he or does he not handle your money?
威利∶有啊!但是呢,打理的不是很好.
Wally: Well yeah!Not very well.
威利∶我怎么会有这样的想法!!
Wally: Bone head idea!!
杰森∶妈妈,对不起.
Jason: Look Mom, I'm sorry.
你也很清楚,
In fairness to you I wouldn't have spent the grand,
如果我不是听了麦琪的废话,我才不会把支票交给他.
if I hadn't listened to Maggie's Prattle.
麦琪∶麦琪的废话!
Maggie: Maggie's Prattle!
杰森∶让我换句话说..
Jason: Let me put it another way...
威利∶如果我是你,我就不会.
Wally: I wouldn't if I were you.
奶奶:我从来就没有期望你会投资.你总是很……很……很……
Grandma: Well, I never expected you to invest.You're usually so...so...so...
麦琪∶吝啬?
Maggie: Cheap?
奶奶:是的.杰森,
Grandma: Right.Jason, I'm really worried about Carol.
我很担心开萝尔.自从她在可怕的车祸中失去她的心上人,
Ever since her young man died in that terrible accident,
她再也不出去约会了;这不好.
she hasn't gone out at all; and that's not right.
她需要别人的帮助,就像你们在爸爸去世后帮助我一样.
She needs someone to do for her, what you did for me after Dad died.
如果不是你,我不会认识威利.
You got me out.If it hadn't been for you, I never would have met Wally.
威利∶哈哈!你的这句话可以弥补你所有的缺点啦.
Wally: Yeah!And that one act makes up for all your other shortcomings.
杰森:妈妈,麦琪,我想她跟肯是合适的,相信我,
Jason: Mom, Maggie, listen if I thought that fixing her up with Ken here
我愿意出一千美元.事实上,我已经出了.
was necessary, believe me, I'd gladly pay a thousand Dollars.In fact, I did.
奶奶:麦琪,
Grandma: So Maggie, here's my idea;
我跟威利准备周六晚上举办一个小小的聚会.
Wally and I are gonna throw a little party on Saturday night.
我会告诉开萝尔肯非常想问……
And I will tell Carol that Ken is just dying to ask...
杰森∶抱歉!
Jason: Excuse me!
奶奶∶邀请她出去.当然,我也会告诉她,聚会对女孩子来说,是非常不错而又安全的去处……
Grandma: ...her out.And I'll mention that the party is a nice, safe place for a girl...
杰森∶妈!
Jason: Mother!
奶奶∶……去.我也会想办法叫肯来约她.
Grandma: ...to be.And I'll get Ken to ask her out.
麦琪∶呀,你怎么样才能让他来约她呢?
Maggie: Oh, how are you gonna get him to do that?
奶奶∶嘿嘿,我就跟他说杰森想加大投资.
Grandma: Well, I will tell him that Jason wants to invest more.
杰森∶打住!
Jason: Hold it!
威利∶喂,你太紧张了.
Wally: Boy, you are tight.
杰森∶不关钱的问题.我只是觉得根本没必要来说这些谎话.
Jason: It's not the money.It's just that these lies aren't necessary.
我是说,如果,如果你邀请开萝尔,
I mean, look, if you wanna invite Carol, you wanna invite Ken,
邀请肯,然后让他们顺其自然就好了.
you put them together and let nature take its course...fine.
奶奶∶麦琪,他说的有道理.
Grandma: Maggie, he's right.
麦琪∶我明白.可能我们俩都太急躁了.
Maggie: I know.Does it irritate you as much as it does me.
奶奶∶宝贝,不愧是心理学家.
Grandma: Well honey, you're the psychiatrist.
杰森∶开萝尔!不需要道歉.
Jason: Carol!No apology necessary.
很多说谎的人都会犯同样的错误.不要有压力.
A lot of lay people would make the same mistake.No pressure.
开萝尔∶知道了.
Carol: Yeah.
杰森:开萝尔,奶奶和威利准备周六晚上办个聚会.
Jason: Carol, Grandma and Wally are gonna have a party on Saturday night.
开萝尔∶哦?是什么特别的日子?
Carol: Oh?What's the occasion?
奶奶∶哦!我们的……我们的……周年纪念.
Grandma: Oh, our...our...anniversary.
麦琪∶我们大家都会去.
Maggie: And we're all invited.
奶奶∶因为晚会的浪漫氛围,
Grandma: And because of the romantic flavour of the evening,
所有参加的人都必须带伴.
it is couples only.
杰森∶妈妈,我们说好的!
Jason: Mom, we agreed!
开萝尔∶我要带男朋友!
Carol: I have to bring a date!
奶奶∶啊,说到这个……啊,
Grandma: Ah, speaking of that...
你刚才见到的那个年轻人,肯,他很想邀请你一起参加,
ah, you know Ken, the young man you just met,
我说的对吗,麦琪?
he is dying to ask you out, isn't he Maggie?
麦琪∶哦!没错.
Maggie: Oh, you bet.
杰森∶麦琪
Jason: Maggie!
威利∶所以,你为什么不和他一起来参加我们的聚会呢?
Wally: Say, why don't you just have him take you to our party?
奶奶∶对呀!
Grandma: Right!
开萝尔∶我真的不知道……
Carol: I really don't know...
杰森∶开萝尔,没人给你压力.
Jason: Carol, there's no pressure here, OK?
如果你不想带男朋友来……
If you don't wanna bring a date sweetheart...
奶奶∶那你就不能参加.
Grandma: You can't come.
开萝尔∶我不能和他约会.
Carol: I can't go out with this guy.
麦琪∶为什么不能?
Maggie: Why not?
开萝尔∶因为我已经找到喜欢的人了.
Carol: Well, because I'm already seeing someone.
杰森∶真的?
Jason: You are?
开萝尔∶真的.是在工作中认识的.
Carol: Yes.Someone from work.
我们已经互相承诺过,不过再去找别的人.
And, well, we promised each other that we wouldn't see other people.
威利∶哦!?
Wally: Oh?
麦琪∶真的?
Maggie: Really?
杰森:明白!开萝尔,
Jason: See!Carol, I think that's just terrific, I think it's very nice...
我觉得太棒了,太好了……你是说,你在跟一个我们没有见过的人约会?
What do you mean, you're going steady with a guy and we haven't even met him?!
开萝尔∶没有找到合适的时机.
Carol: Well, it never seemed like the right time.
杰森∶好了,
Jason: Well, then...I'll be looking forward to meeting your sweet heart
这样的话……我会很期待星期六晚上的见面的.
on Saturday.
开萝尔∶星期六?我想他不能来.
Carol: Saturday?I don't think he can.
杰森∶那随便了,星期天,
Jason: Well then fine.Well then, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday...
星期一,星期二,
I don't care Carol,
星期三...我无所谓的,
but I would like to meet any guy that you consider has to be kept some
开萝尔,我只是想见见你要这么保密的家伙会是什么样!
deep, dark secret!
开萝尔∶好吧,就星期六.
Carol: Right, Saturday's fine.
麦琪∶没有压力.
Maggie: No pressure.
迈克∶嗨!爸爸,我可以借...嗨!嗨威利!你好!
Mike: Hey Dad, can I borrow...Hey!Hey Wally!Hi!
奶奶∶嗨迈克!
Grandma: Hey Mike!
杰森∶嗨!迈克,你知道正在与开萝尔约会的那个家伙吗?
Jason: Hey Mike, what do you know about this guy, Carol's been seeing?
迈克∶肯定另人很失望.只是推测.
Mike: He's desperate.Just a guess.
麦琪:杰森,不告诉我们跟谁约会可不是开萝尔的风格.
Maggie: Jason, it's not Carol's style to keep the guy she's dating a secret.
迈克∶恩,但是呢,从你的角度来看,还是说得通的.
Mike: Yeah, but it sure makes sense from the guys point of you.
本∶我也很期待我们晚上的聚会.我会打上领带的.再见.
Ben: I look forward so, to our evening together.Yes I'll wear a tie.Good bye.
迈克∶你看上去好像很开心?
Mike: What the heck was all that about?
本∶我约了可爱的劳拉林来参加星期六的聚会.
Ben: I just made a date for Saturday night with the lovely Laura Linn.
迈克∶星期六晚上!你是说,你会带女朋友参加奶奶的聚会?
Mike: Saturday night!You mean, you're taking a date to Grandma's party?
本:我想是的.
Ben: Everybody's supposed to.
迈克∶嗨!开萝尔,你会带男朋友参加奶奶的聚会吗?
Mike: Hey Carol, are you taking a date to Grandma's party?
开萝尔∶你也必须带呀!有问题吗?
Carol: You too!What is it with you people?
我可没有干涉你的生活,倒是你却来干涉我的生活.
I don't interfere with your lives, must you interfere in mine.
迈克∶这么说来是真的啦?
Mike: So is that a yes?
开萝尔:是的,是的.
Carol: Yes.Yes.Of course I have a date, I must have a date.
当然我在约会.我要上班跟他见面去了.我的甜心,
I'm gonna see him at work.My sweetheart, my honey man!
我亲爱的.我要拿照片给你看么?
Shall I take pictures for you?
迈克和本∶你的宝贝男人??
Mike and Ben: Honey man??
伊斯塔尔:开萝尔,早上好!
Estelle: Morning Carol.
开萝尔:早上好伊斯塔尔.你注意到没有,
Carol: Morning Estelle.Have you ever noticed,
我们这幢楼里好像男士特别少?
how few men work in this building?
伊斯塔尔:是啊,二十八年来一直这样.
Estelle: Every miserable day for the last twenty eight years!
快点,电梯要来了.
Ah, come on, we'll make room.
开萝尔∶没关系.我等下一部有男人的.
Carol: That's OK Estelle.I'm waiting for one with men.
伊斯塔尔:不会来的.
Estelle That will never come.
大Al∶早上好,开萝尔.
Big Al: Top of the day Carol.
开萝尔∶你好大Al.
Carol: Hi Big Al.
大A1∶怎么了,我的鼻子上有什么脏东西吗?
Big Al: What, is something hanging out of my nose again?
开萝尔∶不,不,没有.大Al,你多大了?
Carol: No, no.Big Al, how old are you?
大Al∶四十三.
Big Al: forty three.
开萝尔∶现在年龄不是问题,对吗?
Carol: Well that's acceptable nowadays, isn't it?
大Al∶我当然希望如此.
Big Al: I sure hope so.
开萝尔∶恩,他们也不会介意的.
Carol: It would serve 'em right, too.
大Al∶谁?
Big Al: Who?
开萝尔∶呵呵,我想问你能不能帮我一个很幼稚的忙.
Carol: Look, I need to ask you for a silly favour.
大Al∶很难吗?
Big Al: Will it hurt?
开萝尔∶稍等.你好.
Carol: Just a second.Hi.
查克:你好.
Chuck: Hi.
开萝尔∶其实,我很少做这样的事情的,我叫开萝尔西维尔,
Carol: Look.I don't usually do things like this, but my name's Carol Seaver,
但是,这个星期六晚上,我必须要带男伴去参加一个聚会……
and I need to be seen somewhere, Saturday night, with a date and...
查克:听上去不错啊.
Chuck: Hey, sounds great!
开萝尔∶真的?
Carol: Really?
查克:是啊.
Chuck: Yeah.
开萝尔∶哦,太好了!难以置信的!
Carol: Well, that's wonderful!That's fabulous!
哦,这样我就不用担心了!就这么说定了?
Oh, does that take the pressure off of me!So, we have a date?
查克∶查克.
Chuck: Chuck.
开萝尔∶查克.很高兴认识你.
Carol: Chuck.Pleased to meet you.
查克∶为了避免误会,
Chuck: Just so we don't have a misunderstanding,
我想先跟你说说我的约会哲学.
I'd like you to know my philosophy on dating.
开萝尔∶我们不必那么急……
Carol: Well, let's not rush...
查克∶不,不,
Chuck: No no no!
不!首先,我不会把约会视为男人和妇女间的社会交往.
First, I don't see dating as social interaction between men and women.
开萝尔∶不是吗?
Carol: No?
查克∶不是,我只是把约会当成性试验的机会.现在既然是你约我,
Chuck: No, I see dating as an opportunity for sexual experimentation.
那就应该由你来定,你爱好什么?嗨!你明白我的意思的.
And since you asked me out, I think it's your call, what's your pleasure?
嗨!等等,你还没有给我你的地址呢……
Hey, you read my mind.Hey wait, you didn't give me your address...
大A1∶啊……怎么样?
Big Al: Ah...so, what is it?
开萝尔∶没什么,我觉得自己太笨了.
Carol: Never mind, I just feel stupid.
大A1∶呵呵,至少你能感觉到一些事情.
Big Al: Well, at least you feel something.
开萝尔:好吧.我需要有人跟我一起去参加周六晚上的聚会.
Carol: OK.Well, I need to be seen somewhere Saturday night with a date...
大A1∶我愿意去.
Big Al: I'll go.
开萝尔∶你愿意?
Carol: You will?
Big Al: Sure.Mother will just have to do her aerobics alone
开萝尔∶哦!谢谢.
Carol: Oh thank you.
大A1∶我的荣幸.
Big Al: My pleasure.
开萝尔∶是家庭式聚会.
Carol: It's a family party.
大A1∶是什么?
Big Al: What is?
开萝尔∶你要带我去的地方.
Carol: Where you're taking me to.
大A1∶他们认为戴领带合适吗?
Big Al: Is a bow tie too crazy for them?
开萝尔∶不,让你这样帮我,
Carol: No.Look, I'm embarrassed about asking you this but...
我实在是很尴尬……可是,这样做对我来说意义重大……
there's more to it than just taking me out...
大A1∶哦!?
Big Al: Oh?
开萝尔∶恩,你能不能假装我们已经约会很多次了?
Carol: Well, could you pretend like we've been out a few times before?
像稳定的情侣一样.
Like we're going steady.
Big Al: Sure, no problem.I've been telling mother, you're my woman for weeks
奶奶∶我看起来怎么样?
Grandma: How do I look?
威利∶很好,我恨不得给所有人打电话,让他们都乖乖的呆在家里.
Wally: So good, I just wanna call everybody and tell 'em to stay home.
奶奶和威利∶哦!太晚了!
Grandma and Wally: Oh, too late!
威利∶我要让他们快点出发.恩,看来我得动点粗了.
Wally: I'll get 'em to leave.I'll do something rude and obnoxious.
奶奶∶杰森通常那样做.哦!本杰明!
Grandma: Jason usually handles that.Oh Benjamin!
本∶奶奶好.这是……
Ben: Hi Grandma.This is...
劳拉∶嗨!妈妈,看起来都还好!没什么怪异的.
Laura-Lynn: Hey Mom, it seems alright!Nothing looks that weird.
你好,我是劳拉林,我妈妈的心肝.
Oh hi, I'm Laura Lin, my mom's nuts.
奶奶∶你好;我是优玛.这个是威利,我的丈夫.
Grandma: Hi, I'm Urma.This is Wally, my husband.
威利∶劳拉林.
Wally: Laura Lin.
劳拉∶你们的房子很多错.
Laura-Lynn: Your apartment is tres chique.
奶奶:噢,是的,谢谢你.喝杯饮料怎么样?
Grandma: Oh, well...err...thank you dear.Would you care for a soft drink?
劳拉∶哦!好的.
Laura-Lynn: Oh that'd be lovely.
威利∶快把灭火器拿来.
Wally: Hurry get the fire-extinguisher.
迈克∶你好,威利...威利,这个是凯特.
Mike: Hi, Wally...Wally, this is Kate.
威利∶呵呵,
Wally: Alright, here's a tip- you'll have a lot more fun out there than
实话跟你说哦--你在外面会比里面玩的更开心哦.
you will in here.
奶奶∶我是优玛,迈克的奶奶.
Grandma: I'm Urma, Mikey's grandmother.
威利∶你好凯特.
Wally: Hi Kate.
凯特∶迈克给我说过很多你们俩的事情.
Kate: Mike's told me so much about you both.
迈克:不要担心,不是什么大事儿.
Mike: Oh, don't worry, it's nothing that'll stand up in a court of law.
凯特∶恩,你们谁的身上有胎记呀?
Kate: Yeah, which one of you has the tattoos?
奶奶∶哦,天啦,你是迈克的女孩么?
Grandma: Oh boy, are you the gal for Mikey?
迈克:嗬嗬,我正要跟你说来着.
Mike: See, that's what I've been trying to tell you, all the way down here.
劳拉林∶你的哥哥,迈克,
Laura-Lynn: Your brother, Mike, is so cute.
好性感.你觉得你也会像他那么性感么?
Do you think there's a chance that you'll wind up looking like him?
本∶那你会像你妈妈一样吗?
Ben: Any chance you're gonna end up looking like your mother?
奶奶∶麦琪呀!
Grandma: Maggie!
麦琪∶你好优玛.
Maggie: Hi Urma.
奶奶∶你好宝贝.
Grandma: Hi sweet heart.
杰森∶他还没来?
Jason: Is he here yet?
奶奶∶谁?
Grandma: Is who here?
麦琪:开萝尔约会的人,一个我们连名字都不知道的人.
Maggie: Oh, the guy Carol's been dating, whose name we don't even know yet.
杰森∶哦,
Jason: Well, I know why she's been hiding him from us too;
he's probably some muscle-bound beach bum in a torn t-shirt
奶奶∶哦!来了!开萝尔!
Grandma: Oh come on!Carol!
杰森∶哦!妈妈,
Jason: Oh come on mother!
别这样!女人总说需要敏感而又有智慧的男人,
Women always say they want somebody sensitive and intelligent,
可是,
and then you end up picking some guy with bulging biceps and raw animal
你们呢,却尽挑些有大肚腩和动物本性的家伙.
passion.
麦琪∶我可没有.
Maggie: I didn't.
迈克∶嗨!,爸爸...爸爸,这个是凯特.
Mike: Hey, Dad...Dad this is Kate.
麦琪∶你好凯特.
Maggie: Hi Kate.Maggie.
凯特∶你好.
Kate: Hi.
杰森∶杰森.
Jason: Jason.
凯特∶你好.我现在终于明白为什么迈克会这么帅了.
Kate: Hi.Well, now I see where Mike gets his good looks.
杰森∶哦!谢谢.
Jason: Oh thanks.
麦琪∶哦!谢谢.
Maggie: Oh thanks.
凯特∶优玛,让我来帮你吧.
Kate: Here, Urma, let me help you with that.
奶奶∶哦!谢谢.
Grandma: Oh, thank you.
杰森∶哈哈,迈克,你一直把她藏在哪里呀?
Jason: Ha ha, Mikey.Where have you been hiding her?
迈克∶爸爸!
Mike: Dad!
麦琪∶杰森,对开萝尔,你说的是"你在和谁偷偷摸摸的交往呢?"而对迈克呢,
Maggie: Sure Jason, to Carol it's, "who've you been sneaking around with?",
却是"哈哈,迈克,你一直都把她藏在哪里?"
but with Mike it's, "ha ha Mikey, where have you been hiding her?"
杰森∶该去开门了.
Jason: This would be a good time to answer the door.
麦琪∶什么门?
Maggie: What door?
杰森∶那个.
Jason: That one.
开萝尔∶我好紧张.
Carol: I'm so nervous.
Big Al: Don't be, whatever happens tonight, we still have each other, honey
杰森∶这一定是开萝尔和……男朋友了.
Jason: So, this must be Carol and...her date.
开萝尔∶大家好,这是大A1.
Carol: Hi everybody, this is Big Al.
大A1∶大家好.
Big Al: Yo everybody.
我冒昧的带了一些茶叶,
I took the liberty of bringing some Sun Tea,
还有一个很特别的自制的惊喜……
and a very special home-made surprise...
开萝尔∶自制的意大利腊肠.
Carol: Home-made salami.
大A1∶我可以用厨房吗?
Big Al: May I use the kitchen?
奶奶∶哦!当然,当然,就在那里.
Grandma: Oh it...it...it's right in there.
开萝尔∶我将帮忙,宝贝儿.
Carol: I'll help, honey.
麦琪∶宝贝儿!
Maggie: Honey!
本∶哇,那个老男人是谁?
Ben: Wow, who's the old dude?
麦琪∶杰森,想想办法.
Maggie: Jason, do something.
杰森∶我不知道说什么.
Jason: I don't know what to say.
麦琪∶但是,以前这些都难不倒你的.
Maggie: Well, that's never stopped you before.
开萝尔∶哦,你真是太好玩了!做的好.
Carol: Oh you are so funny!You're doing great.
大A1∶他们为什么要用眼睛瞪着我?
Big Al: Then why are they all staring at me?
开萝尔∶呵呵,他们从来都没见过有男人会自己做猪肉食品.
Carol: Well, they've never met a man who makes his own pork products.
麦琪∶开萝尔这样做,
Maggie: Maybe this is Carol's way of reacting to all the pressure you've
也许是对你给她施加压力的报复.
put on her.
杰森∶哦!宝贝儿,
Carol: Oh honey, come one, I just wanted to meet the guy.
别这样,我也只是想看看她到底在和谁约会嘛.我也不知道她会带这么个老头来.
I didn't know she was gonna show up with Oscar Myer.
迈克,你了解这个家伙吗?
Mike, what do you know about this guy she's seeing?
迈克∶他会自制熏肉.
Mike: He smokes his own meat.
大A1∶好了.
Big Al: Well winged in.
奶奶∶哦!谢谢,Al.
Grandma: Oh thank you, Al.
大A1∶urma;请用.
Big Al: Urma, please.
奶奶∶哦!对不起的...大A1!
Grandma: Oh sorry...Big Al!
杰森∶Al,我们听说你和开萝尔已经交往了一段时间了....
Jason: Al, we understand that you and Carol have been seeing each other for some time time now...
大A1∶呃...我们...我们,有8个星期了.
Big Al: Err...we...we...eight weeks.
开萝尔和杰森∶八个星期!?
Carol and Jason: Eight weeks!?
大Al:另外,妈妈要请你参加晚宴.
Big Al: Oh, and by the way, Mom wants to have you over to dinner, to celebrate.
开萝尔∶她太好了.
Carol: How sweet.
大A1∶她真的很喜欢你,
Big Al: Well, she likes you.
要不然,
Oh, otherwise she would never have approved of our weekend together in
她也不会答应让我们一起去大西洋城市过周末.
Atlantic City.
麦琪∶什么,什么在大西洋城市共度周末?
Maggie: What, what weekend together in Atlantic City?
威利:你看上去很面熟.打赌我曾经见过你.
Wally: You look so damned familiar.You know, I swear I've seen you before.
杰森∶什么在大西洋城市的周末?
Jason: What weekend in Atlantic City?
威利∶你当过兵吗?
Wally: Were you in the army?
大A1∶是的.
Big Al: You bet.
杰森∶联合还是盟军?
Jason: Union or Confederate?
开萝尔∶别理他们,大A1.
Carol: Come on Big Al.
杰森∶宝贝,你不能换一个吗?
Jason: Don't you take another step, young lady.
开萝尔∶爸爸,我不会让你在这里侮辱我的爱人.
Carol: Daddy, I will not have you stand here and insult my honey man.
大A1∶好了,今天晚上我过的很开心,
Big Al: Well, I had a lovely, lovely evening.
真的很开心.
And I think in time,
我想迟早,你爸妈会忘记年龄的差距而真正的接受我的.
your parents will be able to see past the age difference and accept me.
Carol: Big Al, you do realize that tonight was a pretend date
大A1∶当然明白!我只是希望时间能再长点.
Big Al: Sure.Sure!I just wanna pretend a little longer.
开萝尔∶今天我也很开心.大A1.
Carol: I had a lovely evening tonight, Big.
Big Al: Is it alright if I pretend right up until I get into my
car
开萝尔∶想的美.你还不如在回家的路上一直装呢.
Carol: What the heck.Why don't you pretend all the way home.
迈克∶嗨!听着,妈妈回来后,
Mike: Hey, listen, when Mom gets home,
记得告诉她,我已经付钱给克莉丝的保姆了,用的是我自己的钱.
tell her that I paid for Chrissy's sitter, out of my own pocket.
让她把钱给你,然后,
Get the money, and then tell Dad the same thing, right?
再跟爸爸要一次,听到没?哦,
Oh, and listen, Carol...errm...
还有,我还想问你,你到底是从哪里弄来那个家伙的?
I gotta ask you, where in the heck did you get that guy
开萝尔∶你不喜欢他?
Carol: You didn't like him?
迈克∶哦,不,他人不错.比我想像中的好.
Mike: Oh, no, he was fine.He was actually better than I thought you could get.
本:是的,
Ben: Oh yeah!Well I lied!
我撒谎了!我觉得很不好.
I had a lousy time and you already look like your mother!!
我还是喜欢金发碧眼的美人!
I'm never gonna pick a blonde for anything!
迈克∶好了,开萝尔,说实话吧.
Mike: OK, Carol, what's the real story?
开萝尔:是真的啊!我碰巧遇到成熟美好……
Carol: Real story!I happened to have found someone, mature and wonderful...
迈克∶你是说那个和妈妈住在一起还会自制香肠的家伙!开萝尔,
Mike: Who lives with his mother and makes his own sausages!
别演戏了,你是在和迈克说话!
Carol, come on, this is Mike you're talking to.
开萝尔∶对,我没有和他交往.我只是不喜欢大家.
Carol: OK, I'm not really dating him.I just get so tired of everybody.
我的意思是说,他们的所作所为让我觉得好像不谈恋爱就不对头一样!!但是,
I mean they act like there's something wrong with not dating!!
事实不是农业!我想,我只是想一个人好好的生活,
Well, there isn't!I mean, so I wanna be on my own, I mean,
难道不行吗....我干嘛要跟你说这些?反正你是不会明白的.
why can't that...What am I doing?You don't understand.
迈克∶我也说实话吧,今天晚上我带来的女孩子,
Mike: OK.Kate, the girl that I went to the party with.
凯特,其实我们也根本没有交往.
Well, I'm not really dating her.
开萝尔∶一直奉承你的那一个?
Carol: The one who was all over you?
迈克∶对,她是我一个兄弟的女性朋友,
Mike: Yeah, she was a girl friend of a buddy of mine from acting class...
是表演班的……她只是在演戏而已.
She was acting.
开萝尔∶她不错……
Carol: She was very convincing.
迈克∶说说看.
Mike: Tell me about it.
开萝尔∶但是你为什么……
Carol: But why would you...
迈克∶开萝尔,你知道,
Mike: Carol, I mean...
自从7月份,我..
You know, I just haven't really felt like dating, ever since...July and I...
我们取消婚礼后,
you know....since we called the wedding off.And I...I...
我就没有好好的约会过.并且我……我……我才不想爸妈像对你那样来对我呢.
I didn't want Mom and Dad to do to me, what they're doing to you.
开萝尔∶那你能明白我了.
Carol: So you do understand.
迈克∶恩.不过我要告诉你的是,我真的很喜欢我的假约会.
Mike: Yeah.But, I'll tell you what, I did like my pretend date.
开萝尔∶什么意思?
Carol: What are you saying?
迈克∶我是说它让人觉得不孤独.
Mike: I'm saying that it beat being alone.
开萝尔∶但是,我可不想和别人约会……我这样挺好的!
Carol: But, I don't wanna date anybody...I'm fine!
迈克∶如果你确定的话,就没问题.
Mike: OK, OK, if you're sure.
开萝尔∶我确定!我要跟爸妈说,
Carol: I am sure!
让他们别再来干涉我的事情,
And I'm gonna tell Mom and Dad to keep their noses out of my business;
要不然,我就把罗布洛带回来.
and if they don't, then I'll just bring home...Rob Lowe.
迈克∶恩,爸妈一定会听的,
Mike: Oh, well, that's Mom and Dad and listen...
祝你好运,你放心,
good luck, and I would not mention Rob Lowe to Mom and Dad in your opening
我不会在你的开场白中,跟他们提起你的罗布洛的.
remarks.
麦琪∶开萝尔宝贝儿,让我们谈谈.
Maggie: Carol honey, let's talk.
开萝尔:爸爸妈妈,长话短说.我没有跟大Al约会.
Carol: Mom, Dad, I'll save you some time!Big Al and I have not been dating.
杰森∶恩,我们早就想到了!
Jason: Yeah, we figured that out!
开萝尔∶你什么?
Carol: You what?
麦琪∶猜出来了.很明显,
Maggie: Figured it out.
It was pretty obvious that you brought Al tonight to make a point
开萝尔∶好了,我就是那个意思,同时,我很开心你们终于意识到了.晚安.
Carol: Well, I certainly did, and I'm glad you finally realized that.Good night.
杰森∶哦,等……等……等等,哇,你觉得你这样就完了吗开萝尔?
Jason: Well...wa...wa...wait.Wow wow.You think that says it all, Carol?
开萝尔∶恩,如果说道歉能让你们觉得好过的话,那就跟我道歉吧.
Carol: Well, if it'll make you feel better to apologies...go ahead.
杰森∶恩,也许我应该道歉,
Jason: Well alright.Maybe I should apologies, because these past few months,
因为在过去的几个月,开萝尔,我真的一直特别相信你已经好了.
Carol, I've been wanting very badly to believe that you're OK.
但是,直到今天晚上我才认清事实.
And I didn't realize the truth, until tonight.
开萝尔∶什么事实?你想说什么?
Carol: What truth?What are you talking about?
麦琪∶我们要说的是三迪,和他的意外.
Maggie: We're talking about Sandy, and what happened to him.
开萝尔∶他已经死了,妈妈!他已经死了!你知道的!
Carol: He died, Mom!He died!You can say it!I'm over it.
我已经恢复过来了.但是,今天晚上的事情和三迪一点关系也没有.
But tonight had nothing to do with Sandy!
杰森∶嗨!跟三迪密切相关.
Jason: Hey!It has everything to do with Sandy.
开萝尔∶爸爸,别说了.
Carol: Dad, please.
麦琪∶让他说.
Maggie: Let him talk.
杰森∶那你为什么不谈恋爱?
Jason: Why haven't you dated?
开萝尔∶我不知道.
Carol: I don't know.
我想是因为还没有找到我觉得值得付出的人.
I guess I just haven't found anyone who's worth the trouble.
麦琪∶什么麻烦?
Maggie: What trouble?
开萝尔∶麻烦的事情多着呢!很明显,你们已经很久没有约过会了.
Carol: What trouble!It's obvious you guys have not dated in years.
杰森∶你是害怕跟人约会后,
Jason: I think you're afraid to go out with somebody you might eventually
你会爱上他吧.
care about.I think the thought of losing somebody close to you again,
你害怕再次失去你爱的人.
just terrifies you.
开萝尔∶你是这样认为的?
Carol: You actually think that's what I'm doing?
麦琪∶是,我是.
Jason: Yes, I do.
开萝尔∶妈妈,你相信吗?
Carol: Mom, do you actually believe that?
麦琪∶是,宝贝儿,我也相信.
Maggie: Yes, honey, I do.
开萝尔:不是这样的!我很好!
Carol: Oh, you're wrong!I mean, I'm fine!
我不怕爱上什么人!
I'm not afraid about caring for somebody...of falling in love with somebody!
你们错了!你们都错了!
You're crazy!You're both crazy!
麦琪∶好了,宝贝,好了.
Maggie: Oh, it's OK sweetheart.It's OK.
开萝尔∶我真的不能再次面对那样的打击,妈妈.
Carol: I can't go through that again Mom.
麦琪∶我明白.
Maggie: I know.
开萝尔∶我是那么的爱三迪,我根本不知道改怎么办才好.
Carol: I loved Sandy so much.I don't know what to do.
我也想知道,什么时候我才会觉得好过一点呢?什么时候呢?
I mean, when does this get easier?When?
杰森∶宝贝,并不容易,
Jason: Well, that's the hell of it sweetheart, it never gets easy;
要忘记一个深爱的人不是容易的事情;你只能一点一点,
and the best you can hope for is just, little by little, day by day,
一天一天去学会忘记,
you just keep living.
因为你还要活下去.直到你意识到你自己也可以活的很开心的那一天.
And then one day you're gonna realise that you can be happy again.
肯∶你好西维尔夫人.
Ken: Hi Mrs.Seaver.
麦琪∶哦!你好肯,进来.
Maggie: Oh, hi Ken, come in.
肯∶西维尔医生.
Ken: Dr.Seaver.
杰森∶你好肯!我不知道股票经纪人还会登门造访.
Jason: Hi Ken!I didn't know stock brokers made house calls.
哦!天啊,你不是把我的钱都赔光了吧!
Oh my God, you've lost my money!
肯∶不……不……
Ken: No...no..
开萝尔∶肯,我拿件茄克就好了,马上下来.
Carol: Hi Ken.Let me just grab a jacket.I'll be right down.
肯∶呵呵,开萝尔和我要去赶一场日场,没问题吧?
Ken: Well Carol and I were gonna go a catch a matinee, if that's alright?
麦琪∶哦!当然,没问题.
Maggie: Oh, sure, it's fine.
肯∶对了,既然我已经来了,
Ken: But, as long as I'm here, I might as well tell you;
我最好还是告诉你一声,你买的股票形势不是很好.杰森∶你来我们家就已经让我觉得很开心了!
that stock you bought...well it hasn't been doing so well.
00:22:29,500
Jason: I'm just thrilled you're here!